ecosportdiscoveries.co.in 2014-06-14

# Ford India Private Limited - Privacy and Disclaimer

### Ford India Private Limited Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy

  * What is personal information?
  * How do we collect and use your personal information?
  * What happens if you don't provide personal information?
  * To whom do we disclose personal information?
  * How do we protect personal information?
  * What about information you provide in job applications?
  * Is the personal information we hold accurate?
  * How can you access or correct the personal information we hold about you?
  * Who should you contact if you have concerns about our handling of personal information?
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy

Our Internet Privacy Policy

  * Internet Privacy Commitment
  * Normal web site usage
  * Collection of personally identifiable information
  * Use of "Cookies"
  * Ford's Internet Services
  * Electronic mail sent to us that contains personal information

Disclaimer

### Our Privacy Policy

Ford India Private Limited ("Ford") is committed to responsible privacy practices and to complying with Indian law.  
Our respect for our customers' privacy is paramount. We have policies and procedures to ensure that all personal information is handled in accordance with Indian law.  
This Privacy Policy sets out our policies on the management of personal information - that is, how we collect personal information, the purposes for which we use this information, and to whom this information is disclosed.

#### What is personal information?

Personal information is information that could identify you. Examples of personal information include your name, address, telephone number and email address.

#### How do we collect and use your personal information?

One of the main ways in which Ford collects personal information is from Authorised Ford Dealers. For example, when you purchase a new Ford product, we collect personal information about you from your Authorised Ford Dealer in order to:

  * ensure your purchase of a Ford vehicle is recorded and maintained for warranty purposes;
  * ensure your purchase of a "Ford Solutions" product is recorded and maintained for administration purposes.
  * inform you in the event of a field service action, including a recall, affecting your Ford vehicle;
  * facilitate the provision of roadside assistance services; and
  * contact you to obtain your feedback and to find out your level of satisfaction with our products, services and Dealers through surveys.

If you consent, we may also use your information in order to keep you up to date with information about us and our products and services or to provide you with special offers.

We may also collect personal information from you through transactions you have with us directly, such as through our contact centres, e.g. our Customer Relationship Centre, or online through our website and enewsletters. Where we do this, we will endeavour to inform you why we are collecting your personal information, how we use that information and to whom we intend to disclose it.

#### What happens if you don't provide personal information?

Generally, you have no obligation to provide any personal information requested by us. However, if you choose to withhold requested personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the products and services that depend on the collection of that information. As an example, if you did not provide the personal information requested on your new vehicle purchase, we would be unable to notify you directly of a product recall affecting your vehicle.

#### To whom do we disclose personal information?

We engage third party service providers to perform functions for Ford. Such functions include mailing, delivery of purchases, credit card payment authorisation, trend analysis, market research and promotions.

For our service providers to perform those functions, it is sometimes necessary for us to disclose your personal information to those suppliers. Where disclosures take place, we work with our suppliers to ensure that all personal information we provide to them is kept secure, is only used to perform the task for which we have engaged them and is handled by them in accordance with the National Privacy Principles.

From time to time, we provide statistical information about sales to industry bodies. This may comprise data collected about you and other customers to form aggregate results. However, we will not provide any information that identifies you as our customer.  

#### How do we protect personal information?

At all times, we take great care to ensure your personal information is protected from unauthorised access, use, disclosure or alteration.

We endeavour to ensure that our employees are aware of, and comply with, their obligations in relation to the handling of personal information. Only properly authorised employees are permitted to see or use personal information held by Ford and, even then, only to the extent that it is relevant to their roles and responsibilities.

Your personal information will not be sold to any other organisation for that organisation's unrelated independent use. Further, we will not share your personal information with any organisations, other than those engaged by us to assist us in the provision of our products and services (as described above).

#### What about information you provide in job applications?

If you submit a job application to Ford, we will use the information provided by you to assess your application. Ford may disclose the information contained in your application to contracted service providers for purposes such as screening, aptitude testing, medical testing and human resources management activities. As part of the application process, you may be required to complete a pre-employment health questionnaire. In certain circumstances, you may also be asked to undergo a pre-employment medical assessment. In that case, you will be asked to give specific consent for Ford to disclose your questionnaire to its service providers for the purposes of arranging the medical assessment and for the relevant service providers to disclose the results of the assessment to Ford. If you refuse to provide any of the information requested by Ford, or to consent to the disclosure of the results of your medical assessment to Ford, we may be unable to consider your application. Ford may also ask you whether you agree to your personal information being provided to appropriate Ford suppliers so that you may be considered for positions with those suppliers which are relevant to your qualifications and experience.

#### Is the personal information we hold accurate?

We endeavour to maintain your personal information as accurately as reasonably possible. However, we rely on the accuracy of personal information as provided to us both directly and indirectly. We encourage you to contact us if the personal information we hold about you is incorrect or to notify us of a change in your personal information. Our contact details are set out below.

#### How can you access or correct the personal information we hold about you?

Wherever possible and appropriate, we will let you see the personal information we hold about you and correct it if it is wrong. If we do not allow you access to any part of the personal information we hold about you, we will tell you why.  
If you wish to obtain access to your personal information held by us, or to request us to correct any errors in that information, please contact us by:

  * phoning the Ford Customer Relationship Centre on (04114) 259218
  * faxing the Ford Customer Relationship Centre on (04114) 254279
  * emailing us at [ocadmin@ford.com](mailto:ocadmin@ford.com)
  * or writing to us at : Ford India Private Limited, S.P. Koil Post, Chengalpattu, Tamil Nadu-603 204

#### Who should you contact if you have concerns about our handling of personal information?

If you have any queries or concerns about the manner in which we have handled your personal information, please write to the address mentioned above. We will send you written acknowledgement of your correspondence. We will investigate your query or concern and will advise you of the steps we have taken to answer or resolve it.

#### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time at our discretion and without notice. At any time, the latest version is available from our website at www.india.ford.com  
**Issued August, 2003.**

### Our Internet Privacy Policy

#### Internet Privacy Commitment

This document describes Ford's policy regarding information received about you during visits to our web sites. The amount and type of information received depends on how you use our sites. This website contains links to other sites operated by third parties other than Ford. Ford is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. The inclusion of links does not imply any endorsement of the material on those Web sites or any association with their operators.This privacy statement is for this web site only. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each website that collects your personally identifiable information.

#### Normal web site usage

The only information we collect and store during normal web site usage is the name of your Internet service provider, the web site that referred you to us, the pages you request and the date and time of those requests. We use this information to generate statistics and measure site activity to improve the usefulness of customer visits. During normal web site usage we do not collect or store personally identifiable information such as name, mailing address, email address, or phone number.

#### Collection of personally identifiable information

There are instances where Ford requests personally identifiable information to provide the web site visitor with a service or correspondence (for example, promotions and mailed brochures). This information, such as name, mailing address, email address, type of request and possibly additional information, is collected and stored in a manner appropriate to the nature of the data by Ford and is used to fulfill your request. If you tell us that the information should not be used as a basis for further contact, we will respect your request. The information you provide is used by Ford to improve the services we provide you. It is never provided to any other company for that company's independent use. Information which Ford holds about you may be transferred overseas to Ford's secure facilities. If your information is transferred overseas it will remain subject to strict security safeguards. For further information regarding Ford's handling of your personal information or to request a copy of Ford's privacy policy or information we hold about you, you may email us at [ocadmin@ford.com](mailto:ocadmin@ford.com)

#### Use of "Cookies"

My Ford uses a technology called "cookies" to optimize your on-line experience. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and you'll find cookies at most major web sites. A cookie is a small data element stored by your web browser on your computer system. If selected by you, My Ford will store your username and password in a cookie to enable you to be automatically logged in when you return. My Ford cookies do not store your email address or other personal information about you.

#### Ford's Internet Services

To use Ford's Internet Services, such as My Ford, literature requests, etc., we may require a certain amount of personally identifying information (examples are: name, credit card number, vehicle identification number, address, business name, etc.) that we can use to verify you as a Ford Customer (or to meet your request). We use this information to identify and access data in the existing relationship we have with you to provide you with the requested services. We request electronic mail addresses (email) as an alternate means of contacting you.

#### Electronic mail sent to us that contains personal information

Internet users may decide to send Ford personally identifying information, for example, in a message containing information about your Ford product or service. Ford will only use this information to identify the user as a Ford customer and to determine how to respond to the electronic mail. We will not use this information other than to resolve the matter identified in the email. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy. A revised Privacy Policy will only apply to data collected subsequent to its effective date. Any revisions will be posted at least 10 days prior to its effective date.  

### Disclaimer

Every effort has been made to ensure that the information on this site is correct and up to date, however, Ford India Private Limited ("Ford") does not provide any warranty as to the completeness or accuracy of the information and, subject to applicable laws, does not accept any liability for damages of any kind resulting from the access or use of this site and its contents.

Ford reserves the right to discontinue or change any of the models, prices, colours, materials, equipment or other specifications referred to on this site at any time without notice. Some of the equipment shown or referred to in this site may only be available as an option at extra cost. Always consult an Authorised Ford Dealer for the latest information about a Ford product, and its availability, before placing an order. All prices specified on this site are in Indian Rupees.

Competition product description, specifications and pricing contained herein were correct at the time this material was being prepared for viewing and printing. Specifications have been obtained from competition brochures and other independent published sources. Competition prices used in the comparison section are ex-showroom Delhi.

All information on this site is protected by copyright and other intellectual property rights. No images, text or other content from this site may be distributed or reproduced without prior written approval from Ford.
